Evelyn Coronel

Personal Website | email: me@evecoronel.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | 22607 Hamburg, Germany

SUMMARY

Machine Learning is a devil, and I happen to be a physicist. I'm from Sapucai, Paraguay. I love coding and decoding other's people code. Data Science is science, and my education prepared me to be a scientist. I have experience in classical machine learning, also reinforcement and unsupervised learning. I worked in ML for more than a year and a half so far: industry and scientific research. I'm looking forward to new experiences.

EXPERIENCE

❖ Humboldt-Universität zu Berlin

August 2021 - February 2022

Student Tutor: Tutorial classes for Einführung in Maschinelles Lernen für Physiker (Introduction to Machine Learning for Physicists) for the winter term 2021-2022.

❖ Deutsches Elektronen-Synchrotron DESY

August 2021 - February 2022

Graduate Researcher I learned about the state-of-the-art Graphs Neural Networks papers in physics and explored and experimented with repositories on the topic. Advisor: Prof. Dr. Judith Katzy

❖ Engineering School Research Division (Universidad Nacional de Asunción) RESEARCH INTERN: Data Analysis of Muon Showers with Python and C++.

May 2021 - July 2021

❖ Cortical.com, Inc.

December 2020 - July 2021

Consultant (Remote Work): Focus in Reinforcement Learning & Bayesian Learning, I developed algorithms and helped to debug existing codes.

Remote Internship (April 2020 - June 2020): I learned to approach different problems with a more pragmatic point of view, beyond the mathematical models with unsupervised and reinforcement learning techniques.

❖ The Pierre Auger Observatory

August 2019 - February 2021

Student Intern: During Bachelor's and Master's degrees, I performed data analysis on the atmospheric conditions effects over the measurements of ultra high energy cosmic rays. I searched for large scale anisotropies in the 1 EeV - 2 EeV energy range of the Pierre Auger data, finding anomalies suggesting a dipole within this range. Advisor: Prof. Dr. Silvia Mollerach

❖ Laboratory for Photonics & Optoelectronics

January 2019 - June 2019

STUDENT INTERN: As an undergraduate student, I worked in the first stage of measurements of the Bose-Einstein condensation of polaritons in the Bariloche Atomic Center. I was acknowledged for my work in the following paper https://doi.org/10.1038/s41467-020-18358-z. Advisor: Prof. Dr. Alejandro Fainstein.

EDUCATION

❖ Instituto Balseiro

August 2019 - February 2021

MASTER'S DEGREE IN PHYSICS: I graduated with an overall 7.16/10 GPA.

Dissertation: "Análisis de direcciones de arribo de rayos cósmicos de ultra-alta energía en el Observatorio Pierre Auger" (Analysis of the Arrival directions of Ultra High Energy cosmic rays detected by The Pierre Auger Observatory).

❖ Instituto Balseiro

August 2017 - December 2019

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN PHYSICS: I graduated with an overall 8.16/10 GPA.

SKILLS & INTERESTS

- * Languages/Technologies: Proficient in Python, C++ & Shell Scripting (bash, sed & awk mostly). Familiar with ROOT, CUDA, Git, PyTorch. Experienced in Tensorflow, LATEX, GNU/Linux.
- ★ Interested in Gaming, Data Science, Machine Learning, Philology, Astronomy, Programming and Mental Health Awareness.

Honors & Awards

❖ Scholarship - Comisión Nacional de Energía Atómica

August 2017 - February 2021

❖ Scholarship - Itaipu Binacional

June 2015 - July 2017

State-founded scholarship for outstanding students from low-income families in Paraguay

❖ Silver Medal - Latin American Astronomy and Astronautics Olympiad

August 2014

Olympiad for high school level students in Minas, Uruguay. We were tested for basic astrophysics calculations and water rockets construction.

Conference

♦ 104^a Reunión de la Asociación Física Argentina

September 30^{th} 2019 - October 3^{rd} 2019

104th Argentinian Physics Association Annual Meeting

Poster: Condensado de Bose-Einstein de polaritones en microcavidades ópticas de (Al,Ga)As. (Bose-Einstein Condensation of polaritons in (Al,Ga)As optical cavities)